Register to The Henry Gilbert Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, 1858-1980; Series III; 4.6' (11 boxes)
  - Correspondence - To Gilbert, III.B
    - From others, III.B.2
      - F.H. Gilson, 1899-1900 (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - Farnsworth, Charles H., 1915 Apr (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - Farwell, Arthur, 1899-1925 (Box 31, Folder 53)
        See also: Wa-Wan Press.
      - Fiedler, Max, 1911-1912 (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - Fillmore, Parker, 1925 Feb 4 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Fletcher, Alice, 1907 Feb 15 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Flood, W.H. Grattan, 1918 Dec 9 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Forum, 1923-1928 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Fox, Lois, ca. 1917 Sep 19 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Francis, Pauline, no date (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Frankfurter Museums-Gesellschaft, no date (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Freeman, 1921 Apr 7 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Freer, Eleanor Everest, ca. 1923 Jun 12 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - Frothingham, Robert, 1922 Dec (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - F-?, S.I., 1921 (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - G. Schirmer, 1917-1925; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 55)
        See also: Oscar G. Sonneck.
      - Galli, Rosina, 1917 Oct (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Gallo, Stanislao, 1917 Jul 20 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Gatti-Casazza, Giulio, 1917 Aug 30 (Box 31, Folder 56)
        See also: Metropolitan Opera.
      - Gilman, Lawrence, 1921-1928 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Ginn and Company, 1911-1924; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Golden Rooster, ca. 1919 Jun 6 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Goodwin & Tabb, 1921 Jul (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Gray, H.W.
        See: H.W. Gray.
      - Green, S.D., 1923 Jan 3 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Greene, Jerome D., 1923-1924 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Griffes, Charles, no year Feb 4 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - Grove's Dictionary of Music and Musicians, 1918 Aug 7 (Box 31, Folder 56)
      - H.L. Chapman, 1916 Feb 16 (Box 31, Folder 57)
      - H.W. Gray, 1917-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 57)
      - Hadley, Henry-Kimball, 1897-1923; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 58)
      - Hale, Philip, 1917-1926; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 59)
      - Hallé Concerts Society, 1921-1923 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Hammond, F.T., 1914-1926 (Box 31, Folder 60)
        See also: Composer's Music Corporation; and III.G. Re Gilbert's Collaboration with Edward S. Curtis.
      - Hare, Maud Cuney, 1926 Dec 12 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Harmati, Sandor, ca. 1926 Aug 28 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Harriman, Mrs. E.H., 1923 Feb 1 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Harris, Emily, 1923 Jan 4 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Harris, George A., 1926 Sep 4 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Harris, Forbes & Company, 1916-1929; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 61)
        See also: Chicago Railways Company.
      - Harris Trust and Savings Bank, 1926 Jul 15 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Harvard College, 1897-1910 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Harvard College Library, 1922-1923 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Harvard Glee Club, 1923 May 24 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Harvard University Orchestra, no year Mar 21 (Box 31, Folder 61)
        See also: Nicolas Slonimsky.
      - Hayden, J. Willard, Jr., 1924 Jul 21 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Haytin, Boris, 1921 Mar (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Heilman, William C., 1927 (Box 31, Folder 62)
        Contains jottings by Henry Gilbert.
      - Henderson, W.J., 1923 Jan 31 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Hill, Edward Burlingame, 1913-1926 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Hincks, David A., 1922 May 20 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Hinds, Hayden & Eldredge, 1921-1922 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Hipsher, Edward Ellsworth, 1925 Dec 7 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Hoffmann, William C.
        See: People's Symphony Orchestra.
      - Homiletic Review, 1926 Dec (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Houghton Mifflin, 1905-1926 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hubbard, Vincent V., no date (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hughes, Edwin, no year Sep 26 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hughes, Rupert, 1903 Apr 3 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Humiston, ?, no date (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hunter, Walter C., 1920-1921 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hyde, Alice C., no date (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Hyde, E. Francis, 1907 Apr 5 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Iarecka, Louise Llewellyn, no date (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - Inter-Continental Transportation, 1922 Dec (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - International, 1913 Oct 28 (Box 31, Folder 64)
        See also: César Saerchinger.
      - International Composer's Guild, 1921-1922 (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - International Society for Contemporary Music, 1926-1927 (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - Isaacs, Lewis M., 1922 (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - Jacobi, Frederick, no date (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - Jackson, George P., 1917-1918 (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - Jameson, Elizabeth, 1921 Mar 4 (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - John Church Company, 1924-1928 (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1925-1927 (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - Johnson, Frederic Ayres, no year Apr 28 (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Johnston, Charles, 1902-1916; 10 or more items. (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Johnston, Vera (Mrs. Charles), 1902-1908 (Box 31, Folder 67-68)
        Photo enclosed.
      - Jones, Robert E., no year Jun 16 (Box 31, Folder 68)
      - Juilliard Musical Foundation, no date (Box 31, Folder 68)
      - Kahn, Otto, 1916-1927; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 69-70)
      - Kallen, H.W., no date (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Kelly, Edgar Stillman, 1918 Feb 1 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Kelley, J., no date (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Kenneth-Brown, Demeter, 1927 Jun 8 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Kindler, Hans
        See: Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge.
      - Kingsbury, Edw. R., 1895 Dec 12 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1927 Apr 19 (Box 32, Folder 71)
        See also: Boston Symphony Orchestra.
      - Krehbiel, Henry Edward, 1907-1923 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Kuhn, Loeb & Compnay
        See: Otto Kahn.
      - La Follette, Suzanne, no year Dec 22 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Lai-?, Harriet, no date (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Langdon, William Chauncey, 1914-1918 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Langley, Allan Lincoln, 1922 Jan 18 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Leider, Leo, 1913-1924 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Lewis, ?, 1911 Nov 3 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Library of Congress, 1897-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 73)
        See also: Carl Engel and Oscar G. Sonneck.
      - Lilienthal, A.W., 1913-1918 (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Llewellyn, Louise
        See: Louise Llewellyn Iarecka.
      - Loeffler, Charles Martin, 1917-1918 (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Lowell, A. Lawrence, 1924 Mar 28 (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Luce, Allena, 1920 Oct 11 (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - Lurr-?, Harriet, no date (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - McCormick, Edith W., 1922 May 16 (Box 32, Folder 74)
      - McDougall, Carl R., 1911 Aug 14 (Box 32, Folder 74)
      - MacDowell, Edward A., 1890-1899 (Box 32, Folder 75)
      - MacDowell, Marian, 1906-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 76)
        Some copies laid in.
      - MacDowell Memorial Colony, 1915 Aug 15 (Box 32, Folder 76)
      - Madison, H.M., no date (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Makechnie, Ernst, no date (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Manley, Frederick, 1904 (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Marsh, Elizabeth, no date (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Martens, Frederick H., 1917 Mar 22 (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1926 Aug 29 (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Mason, Henry L., 1918-1922 (Box 32, Folder 77)
        See also: Mason & Hamlin.
      - Mason & Hamlin, 1923 (Box 32, Folder 77)
      - Massachusetts. Office of Clerk of the Courts. (County of Middlesex, East Cambridge), 1928 Mar 27 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Mayberry, Hallowell & Hammond, 1915 Apr 10 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Maynard, Tom, no date (Box 32, Folder 78)
        First page missing.
      - Meeker, Ezra, 1923 Jul (Box 32, Folder 78)
        Clippings enclosed.
      - Mellor, Jacqueline, 1923-1926 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Melos, 1921-1922 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Men of Mark in Massachusetts, 1907 Jun 10 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Mengelberg, Willem, 1926 Oct 23 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Mercantile Trust Company, 1926 Jun (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - Metropolitan Opera Company, 1917-1927; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 79)
        See also: Giulio Gatti-Casazza.
      - Mifflin, Houston (?), 1905 Oct 25 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Miller, Gerrit S., Jr., 1897-1925 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Milwaukee University School, 1926 Sep (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1919 Apr (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Mitchell, George H., 1906 Oct (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Moe, Henry Allen
        See: John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.
      - Möll, Hendrick, no date (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Monteux, Pierre, 1918-1928 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Moody, Harriet (Mrs. William Vaughn), 1922 May (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Morand, Josephine Fiala, 1917 Oct 24 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Morse, Jeska Swartz, no date (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Motion Picture Producers & Distributors of America, 1923 Mar 16 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Motzorongo Company, 1926-1929 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - Mueller, Joseph, 1917 Dec 5 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Mukeji?, Dhan G-al, no year May 18 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Munson, Audrey, 1923 Feb 3 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Murphy, Jeanette Robinson, 1906-1913 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Music & Youth, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Music Trade News, 1927 Mar 3 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Musical America, 1916-1920 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Musical Courier, 1918-1930; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 82)
      - Musical Fund Society of Philadelphia, ca. 1927 (Box 32, Folder 82)
      - Musical Quarterly, 1915-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 82)
      - Narodny, Ivan, 1914-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 83)
        See also: Robert W. Chanler.
      - Narodny, Maria Mieler, 1924 Oct 7 (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - National Academy of Music, 1918 Jun 17 (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - National Bank of the Republic of Chicago, 1927 Feb 2 (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - National Federation of Musical Clubs, 1919 Apr (Box 32, Folder 83)
        Includes 2 copies.
        See also: Charles Wakefield Cadman.
      - National Society of Music, 1914-1917; 10 or more items. (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - Naumberg, Walter, 1927 Apr 8 (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - Neuendorff, Adolph, 1897 May (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - Nevins, Anna L., 1923 Feb 18 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - New England Storage Warehouse Company, 1927 May 9 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - New York American, 1919 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - New York Times, 1927 Aug 6 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - Ney, Lou (pseudonym?), 1928 Jun 28 (Box 32, Folder 85)
        See also: IV. CLIPPINGS.
      - Nordamerikanischen Sängerhandes, 1923 Nov 12 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - North American Indian, 1920 Sep 8 (Box 32, Folder 85)
      - O'Connor, Amanda, 1914 Nov 17 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Ojai Valley Music Festival, 1925 Jun 16 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Oliver Ditson, 1924-1926 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Opera, 1913 Nov 15 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Opera in our language Foundation, 1923 Jul (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Opera Magazine, 1914 may 6 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Ortho, John, 1926 Feb 27 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Ortiz, Catalina Marfa, 1926 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Osgood, Alice M., 1891 Oct (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Otheman, Mary, 1922 Sep 10 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Oumansky, Alexandre, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Oxford University Press, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 86)
      - Paderewski Fund for American Composers, 1922 Jul 20 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Palais, Joseph, 1929 Jul (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Parker, H.T., 1922 Nov 21 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Patterson, Frank, 1917 Oct 5 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Paul, Elliot H., 1922 Apr 1 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Pease, Livingston?, 1917 Aug 2 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Penfield, Roderic C., 1913 May 20 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - People's Symphony Concerts, 1913 Oct 10 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - People's Symphony Orchestra, 1928 Mar 2 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Phelps, George Turner, 1903-1919 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Philadelphia Orchestra
        See: Leopold Stokovski.
      - Philharmonic Society of New York, 1917 Oct 29 (Box 33, Folder 87)
        See also: Joseph Stansky.
      - Phonograph Monthly Review, 1926-1927 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Phonograph Publishing Compnay, 1926 Nov 10 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Pilgrim Tercentenary Commission, 1921 Sep 2 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Pogany, Willy, no date (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Pope, W.M., 1907 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Press Association Compilers, 1912-1917 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Presser Foundation, 1925-1927 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Prince, Benjamin, 1912-1914 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Pult und Taktstock, 1927 Mar 23 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Purdy, Constance, no year Aug 4 (Box 33, Folder 88)
      - Rabaud, Henri, 1918 Dec 12 (Box 33, Folder 89)
      - Ranck, Edwin Carty, 1912-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 33, Folder 89)
      - Reed, Frank L., 1917 Dec (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Reiner, Fritz, 1926 Nov 27 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Reis, Claire R., 1927 Sep 30 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Rich, Thaddeus, 1920 Apr 21 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Richardson, ?, ca. 1911 Jul 15 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Ringrose, Jerome Arthur, 1912 Jul 8 (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Ripley, Frederic H., no date (Box 33, Folder 90)
      - Robinson, Edward Arlington, 1917-1928 (Box 33, Folder 91)
      - Robinson, Lennox, ca. 1911 Sep 27 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Robinson, Lincoln, 1928 Mar 28 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Robinson, Thomas P., 1914-1920 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Rogers, Blanche E., no year Feb 27 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Rogers, Clyde L., 1924-1926 (Box 33, Folder 92)
        See also: VIII. MUSICAL GAMES.
      - Ruggles, Carl, 1908 Apr 30 (Box 33, Folder 92)
        See also: VI. SCRAPBOOKS.
      - Ryan, Arthur, 1922 (Box 33, Folder 92)
      - Saerchinger, César, 1914-1919; 10 or more items. (Box 33, Folder 93)
        See also: Associated Authors and Compilers; Current Literature Publishing Company; Current Opinion; International; Musical Courier; National Academy of Music; National Society of Music; and Society of Authors and Editors.
      - Sanford, C., 1922 Jun 16 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Sauthian, Olin M.?, 1928 Feb (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Schelling, Ernst, 1919 Nov 5 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Schenck, Elliott, 1903 Feb 14 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Schirmer's Musical Quarterly, 1914 (Box 33, Folder 94)
        See also: Oscar T. Sonneck.
      - Schupp, Emily, 1914-1917 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Schwab, Charles M., 1919 Dec 1 (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Schwerké, Irving, no date (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - Sesquicentennial International Exposition, 1926 Mar (Box 33, Folder 94)
      - See, A.M., 1928 May 1 (Box 33, Folder 94)
        See also: Eastman School of Music.
      - Shapleigh, Bertram, 1904-1910 (Box 33, Folder 95)
        See also: VI. SCRAPBOOKS. David Bispham.
      - Shapleigh, Mrs. Bertram?, no date (Box 33, Folder 95)
      - Sharp, Cecil, 1917-1919 (Box 33, Folder 95)
      - Sheldon, Stuart, 1924 Mar 24 (Box 33, Folder 95)
      - Shepherd, [Arthur?], 1911 Jun 27 (Box 33, Folder 95)
      - Silver, Burdett & Company, 1913-1925 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Sinfonia, 1916 Dec 15 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1927 Apr 28 (Box 33, Folder 96)
        See also: Harvard University Orchestra.
      - Smallens, Alexander, 1918-1920 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Smallens, Anna, 1919 Feb 2 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Smith, David Stanley, no year Apr 4 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Smith, John B., 1885 Aug 9 (Box 33, Folder 96)
      - Society for Publication of American Music, 1920 Mar 15 (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - Society of American Musicians and Composers, 1899 (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - Society of American Singers, 1918 Jul 19 (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - Society of Authors and Editors, 1914 Dec 15 (Box 33, Folder 97)
      - Sonneck, Oscar G., 1914 (Box 33, Folder 97)
        See also: G. Schirmer; Library of Congress; and Musical Quarterly.
      - Spalding, Walter R., 1913-1928; 10 or more items. (Box 33, Folder 98)
      - Spear, Annah G. (Mrs. Bill), 1913-1918 (Box 33, Folder 99)
      - Spear, Bill, 1901-1911 (Box 33, Folder 99)
      - Spencer, Mrs. L-?, no date (Box 33, Folder 99)
        In Henry Gilbert's hand?
      - Speyer, Leonora, no date (Box 33, Folder 99)
      - Stanhope Press
        See: F.H. Gilson.
      - Steele, Willis, 1917 Dec 22 (Box 33, Folder 100)
      - Stoeckel, Carl, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 100)
      - Stoeckel, E.B., no year Jun 10 (Box 33, Folder 100)
      - Stokowski, Leopold, 1914-1919 (Box 33, Folder 100)
      - Stowe, Emma G., 1882-1899; 10 or more items. (Box 33, Folder 101-104)
      - Stransky, Josef, 1914-1916 (Box 33, Folder 105)
        See also: Philharmonic Society of New York.
      - Stratton-Porter, Gene, 1920-1921 (Box 33, Folder 105)
      - Summers, W.B., 1891 Jun 29 (Box 33, Folder 105)
      - Swift, Wiley P., 1911 May 23 (Box 33, Folder 105)
      - Talbot, W.T., 1900 Jun (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Tausig, Karl, 1911 Jan 13 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Taylor, Deems, 1917 Mar 18 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Teall, Dorothy J., 1919 Aug 9 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Theodore Presser Company, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Torrey, Edith E., no date (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Townes, Earl, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Townsend, John Wilson, 1933 Jun 13 (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Tracy, E.S., no date (Box 34, Folder 106)
      - Turcrynowicz, Laura de Gordawa, 1916-1921 (Box 34, Folder 107)
      - United States. Department of Agriculture, 1907 Jul 30 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - United States. Patent Office. Department of Commerce, 1926 May 11 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - United States. House of Representatives, 1917-1920 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - United States. Senate, 1924 Oct 13 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - United States. Treasury Departement, 1900 Feb 15 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - University of Rochester (Library), 1928 Mar 20 (Box 34, Folder 108)
      - Varèse, Edgard
        See: International Composer's Guild.
      - Varney, W.H., 1923 Oct (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - Vernon, ?, 1924 Oct 1 (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - Vickers, Sydney G., 1929 Dec 21 (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - Victor Talking Machine Company, 1915 Feb 16 (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - Vosburgh, Wande? B., 1922 Oct (Box 34, Folder 109)
      - Wa-Wan Press, 1907-1911 (Box 34, Folder 110)
        See also: Arthur Farwell.
      - Walcott, Samuel Frye, 1919 Jan 17 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Wardwell, Mrs. F.S., 1919 Sep 20 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Whaling Film Corporation, 1920 Oct (Box 34, Folder 110)
        See also: Elmer Clifton; and Arthur Ryan.
      - White, Elise Fellows, no date (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - White, Paul Dudley, 1927 Oct 24 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Whiting, Arthur, 1915 Mar 18 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Whitney & Elwell, 1927 Aug 13 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Who's Who in Music, 1929 Jan 14 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Wilcox, Jerome K., 1928 Feb 7 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Willcox, Louise Collier, 1928 Jul 21 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Williamson, Thames, 1924 Jun 30 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Women's Musical Alliance, 1917 Oct 13 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Womer, Samuel?, 1916 Feb 8 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Wood, Henry 1., 1923-1924 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Woolley, H.W., no date (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Wyman, Henry A., 1916 Mar 17 (Box 34, Folder 110)
      - Yasgur, Arthur, 1915 Jun 19 (Box 34, Folder 111)
      - Yezursky, Anzia, 1920 Nov 7 (Box 34, Folder 111)
      - Ziegler, Edward, 1920 Apr 14 (Box 34, Folder 111)
        See also: Metropolitan Opera Company.
      - Unidentified correspondence, etc., 1892-1925; 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 111)
        Includes 2 copies of 3 sheets (typescript) of excerpts from letters to Henry Gilbert from several people.
  - Correspondence - Between Mrs. Gilbert and Others, III.C
    - From Mrs. Gilbert, 1912-1953; III.C.1
      Mostly typescript (copies) and some manuscript copies of letters from Mrs. Gilbert to composers, publishers, etc. Copies have been made of letters in poor condition.
      - A, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 112)
      - B, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 113)
      - C, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 114)
      - D, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 115)
      - E-F, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 116)
      - G, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 117)
      - H-J, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 118)
      - K-L, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 119)
      - M-N, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 120)
      - O-P, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 121)
      - R, 10 or more items. (Box 34, Folder 122)
      - S, 10 or more items. (Box 35, Folder 123)
      - T, 10 or more items. (Box 35, Folder 124)
      - U-W, 10 or more items. (Box 35, Folder 125)
      - Typescripts (copies) of form letters from Mrs. Gilbert to others (Box 35, Folder 126)
      - Unidentified letters, 10 or more items. (Box 35, Folder 127-128)
    - To Mrs. Gilbert, 1889-1953; III.C.2
      - A, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 129)
        Includes 10 items from Percy Lee Atherton.
      - B, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 130-131)
        Includes 2 items from Ernst Bloch.
      - C, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 132)
        Includes 3 items from Converse.
      - D, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 133)
        Includes 10 items from Downes.
      - E, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 134)
      - F, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 135)
        Includes 2 items from Farwell and 4 items from Foote.
      - G, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 136)
        Includes items from Goodrich and Gruenberg.
      - H, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 137-138)
        Includes 6 items from Hadley, 10 from Hanson, and 1 from Heilman.
      - I (Box 36, Folder 139)
      - J, 10 or more items. (Box 36, Folder 140)
      - K (Box 36, Folder 141)
        Includes 2 items from Otto Kahn.
      - L, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 142)
        Includes letter from Loeffler.
      - M, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 143-144)
        Includes items from Frederick Manley and Daniel Gregory Mason.
      - N, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 145)
        Includes items from Narodny.
      - 0 (Box 37, Folder 146)
        Includes letter from Ormandy.
      - P, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 146)
      - R, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 147)
        Includes 3 items from Ranck.
      - S, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 148)
        Includes items from Saerchinger, Slonimsky, David Stanley Smith, and Spalding.
      - T (Box 37, Folder 149)
        Includes telegram from Toscanini.
      - U-V (Box 37, Folder 150)
      - W-Y, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 151)
      - Unidentified, 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 152)
      - Copies of letters to Mrs. Gilbert., 10 or more items. (Box 37, Folder 153-159)
        Many have been copied onto acid free paper.
  - Correspondence - Between Isolde Therese Gilbert Horton and Others, III.D
    - Correspondence, 1919-1980; 10 or more items. (Box 38, Folder 160-162)
  - Correspondence - Between Family, III.E
    - Correspondence between various Gilbert relatives, 1895-1942; 10 or more items. (Box 38, Folder 163-168)
  - Correspondence - Between Family and Others, III.F
    - Correspondence, 1858-1946; 10 or more items. (Box 38, Folder 169-170)
  - Correspondence re Gilbert's Collaboration with Edward S. Curtis, III.G